<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on KLN</title>
    <link>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on KLN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 08:53:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bash scripting - set command </title>
      <link>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/bash-set-e/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 08:53:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/bash-set-e/</guid>
      <description>🖥 Bash scripting - set command and its usage   In this post we will see what is set in bash scripting We will also discuss when to use set -e.   Set command Use the set command to set or unset values of shell options and positional parameters. You can change the value of shell attributes and positional parameters, or display the names and values of shell variables using set command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boto3 Resource, Client and Session</title>
      <link>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/boto3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 01:23:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/boto3/</guid>
      <description>Core concepts of Boto3   There are few concepts of boto3 (aws sdk) like Session, Resource, Client, Meta, Collections, Paginators In this post we will discuss about the kehy difference between Resource, Client and Session   Session  A session manages state about a particular configuration. By default, a session is created for you when needed. However, it&amp;rsquo;s possible and recommended that in some scenarios you maintain your own session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins as a Container</title>
      <link>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/jenkins-as-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 01:23:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/jenkins-as-docker/</guid>
      <description>Run jenkins as a container with the stateful volume! Why docker as a container 🤔  It&amp;rsquo;s helps simplify the installation process. Decrease dependency errors. The Turnaround time for an Jenkins server installation is just few minutes. Cross platform compatible.  Why do we need a stateful volume!🤨  Containers are often an ephemeral where in Jeknins we need to save our workloads even if we are not using it regularly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker-container-howitworks</title>
      <link>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/docker-cli-container-howitworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 08:53:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/docker-cli-container-howitworks/</guid>
      <description>🐳 Docker container creation - How it works!   In this post we will see what is happening when we run a command # docker container run -it -d nginx We will also discuss some components involved during the container creation process   Docker CLI (docker) 💻  Docker CLI (docker)
/usr/bin/docker Docker is used as a reference to the whole set of docker tools and at the beginning, it was a monolith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubectl alias</title>
      <link>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/kubectl-alias/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 08:53:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lforlinux.github.io/posts/kubectl-alias/</guid>
      <description>Play with kubernets at ease! Alias? What,Why 🤔   An alias is a (usually short) name that the shell translates into another (usually longer) name or command. Aliases allow you to define new commands by substituting a string for the first token of a simple command. It can be used to avoid typing long commands or as a means to correct incorrect input. For common patterns it can reduce keystrokes and improve efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
